Defense map?
城防图
He came from Pei's Mansion,
他出身裴府
which is the former Minister of Defense Pei Wujiang's private house.
裴府又是前任司军裴武姜的私宅
It's not hard for him to get the defense map.
能搞到城防图倒也不是什么难事
He aims to frame me for unlawful possession of the defense map?
他这是要栽赃我私藏城防图啊
Luckily, we've found it out in time,
幸亏我们发现得早
or he'd have his way.
不然就让他得逞了
Put it back.
原路放回去
Without helping him achieve his aim,
不成全他
I couldn't achieve mine.
怎么成全我呢
I've had enough of
少城主这个位子
acting as the Crown Princess.
我也是坐了够久了
I hope Yingying can do it well
只希望婴婴这回能够
this time
加点力
and won't let me down.
别让我失望
Your Highness.
郡主
Defense map?
城防图
Your Highness, we don't know who reported it.
郡主 这密报也不知是谁送来的
What if it's false,
万一像上次
just like the spy case last time?
密探事件一样作伪的话
If it's false, I'll just be scolded at worst.
假的 我不过是挨一顿训斥
But if it's true,
真的
Chen Qianqian will have to
陈芊芊的少城主之位
give up her position as the Crown Princess.
就只有拱手相让了
Do you mean...
那郡主的意思
Concentrate forces. We'll go to Yueli Mansion.
集结人马 去月璃府
Got it.
是
Your Highness,
启禀二郡主
no relevant evidence has been found.
没有找到相关证据
How could it be possible?
怎么会没有
Is the tip-off false?
难道 密报是假的
Someone from Yueli Mansion reported that
刚刚月璃府有人告发
the Crown Princess wanted to rebel.
少城主 谋反
Who's the informant?
告密人是谁
Su Ziying?
苏子婴
Hasn't Minister Pei asked you
你不是受了裴司学的嘱托
to be always loyal to the Crown Princess?
对少城主忠心不二的吗
It's true I work for the Crown Princess,
小人虽是少城主的人
but as one of the citizens of Huayuan City,
但也是花垣城子民
I can't do nothing when she refused to come to her senses.
不能看着少城主执迷不悟
I saw her hide the defense map
小人打理书房时亲眼所见
when I was cleaning up her study.
三公主私藏城防图
Your Highness.
少城主啊
Bad news. Our mansion is being searched.
不得了了 我们家被抄了
Why are you making a noise?
吵吵什么呀
It once happened.
又不是没被抄过
Let me know when they're done.
抄完了叫我啊
But...
不
Your Highness,
少城主
you always bring trouble to yourself.
你这引火烧身的喜好
It makes things so difficult for me.
真是为难死我了
It's not there.
那边没有
I've told you
我都说了
to let me know after they're done.
抄完了再叫我
I haven't done my make-up yet.
妆都不服帖呢今天
Your Highness, the defense map is hidden here.
二郡主 城防图就藏在这里
Yingying,
婴婴
you finally did something great.
总算是干成一件大事了
Ziying, don't you have a guilty conscience?
苏兄 你到底有没有良心
How can you do this to the Crown Princess?
做出这种对不起少城主的事
I shouldn't have treated you as my brother.
枉我把你当兄弟一般
You're not faithful!
你竟这样不讲义气
I know where my loyalty lies.
大义当前
I'm faithful to our young master
小人虽然忠于公子
and the Third Princess,
忠于三公主
but I can't act against my conscience.
但也不能昧着良心做事
That's right.
没错
The map is hidden by me.
这个图就是我藏的
He didn't frame me.
没有任何人陷害我
Chuchu, investigate it and find the truth out.
那个 二姐 你赶紧查吧
When this case is settled,
查完这事尘埃落定了
let's go back to places where we should go.
咱俩也就各归各位
Open the box.
开箱
Look carefully
好好看看啊
and find out what I've hidden.
好好看看我是藏了什么个好宝贝
Maybe it'll make me lose my reputation,
说出来能让人神共愤 名誉扫地
be considered shameless
被评德行有亏
and even have to step down from my position.
立刻退位让贤的好宝贝
Young Master, don't worry.
少君放心
I've replaced the defense map
小人已经将城防图
with something else.
换成了别的东西
As long as I'm here,
有我在
Su Ziying won't have a chance to hurt Qianqian.
苏子婴别想伤害芊芊
Have you sent someone to notify Pei Heng?
去请裴恒了吗
Yes, I have.
早就去请了
I think he'll be here soon.
算算时间也应该到了
I'd like to see
我倒要看看
if Pei Heng dares to see Qianqian again
此事一出
as this thing happens.
裴恒还有什么脸面在芊芊面前
It'll really make you lose your reputation,
的确会名誉扫地
but you don't have to step down from your position.
但还不至于退位让贤
What?
不至于
Impossible.
那不能够
Go have a look. All of you go have a look.
去看吧 都去看看
Well.
那什么
It won't incur popular indignation.
不会人神共愤的
It's human nature, after all.
毕竟也是人之常情嘛
-Human... -Right?
常 是吧
It's shameful, indeed.
确实德行有亏
Exactly.
那是
But the Crown Princess is just that type of person.
不过咱们少城主就是这样的人
Definitely.
可不吗
There is nothing to be surprised at.
没什么好奇怪的
Yeah.
那是
It's just a defense map.
不就是张城防图吗
Why are you looking at me like that?
干吗要这么看着我
The Crown Princess deserves her reputation.
不愧是少城主啊
They're portraits.
是画像
I think
看这样
it's Minister Pei.
画的像是裴司学
She hid the portraits of
少城主竟然偷着藏
Minister Pei in secret.
裴司学的画像
Shut up.
闭 闭嘴
Don't say another word.
不 不准说
No. Chuchu.
不 不对 二姐
I didn't hide these.
这 这不是我藏的图
I didn't. Someone wants to frame me.
不对 有人陷害我
The two of you worked together
你们主仆二人
to make a fool of me.
联合起来戏耍我
Your Highness, you got it wrong.
二郡主 不是的
I didn't mean to fool you.
小人绝对没有戏弄您的意思
Who did it?
谁干的
Your Highness.
少城主
Your Highness, Minister Pei is here.
少城主 裴司学来了
Go ahead.
继续说
The Crown Princess is full of cunning tricks.
少城主诡计多端
She must have become aware of something
想必 是她有所察觉
so that she's replaced it to get out of trouble.
才临时调包 甩脱罪名
I did see her hide the defense map.
她私藏城防图是小人亲眼所见
Su Ziying,
苏子婴
you reported Qianqian for stealing Huayuan City's confidential documents?
是你告发芊芊窥视花垣城机密
Young Master, I saw it with my own eyes.
公子 小人真的亲眼所见
Where is the map?
图呢
It...
这
Qianqian.
芊芊
Pei Heng,
裴恒
please trust me.
你真的要相信我
I'm innocent. I...
我真的是清白的 我
Such stuff is found in your study.
在你书房抄出这种东西
Shouldn't you care about Minister Pei?
难道就不该关心裴司学的清白吗
Yes, I should.
对 该 该关心
So, both of us are innocent.
所以我们两个都是清白的
Su Ziying, look at what you've done.
苏子婴 你干的好事
I have no idea.
小人不知
The Third Princess set me up.
小人是遭三公主陷害
She's scheming.
三公主心机深重
She showed me the defense map on purpose
给小人看城防图
and then replaced it with portraits.
却私自换成画像
She seduced me into bringing a false charge.
诱小人诬告
Shut up.
你可闭嘴吧你
You're the culprit.
坏就坏在你身上
Su Ziying must have ganged up with the Second Princess,
苏子婴肯定是和二郡主里应外合
or she couldn't have known the Crown Princess hid these portraits.
否则 二郡主怎知我少城主藏图
She's had the whole mansion searched.
还来抄家呢
What are you talking about?
你说什么
I did this alone.
是小人一人所为
It has nothing to do with the Second Princess.
与二郡主无关
Chen Qianqian is so brutal. She doesn't deserve to be the Crown Princess.
陈芊芊为人残暴不仁 德不配位
I framed her
小人此前与她有私怨
because she bullied me.
才栽赃陷害
It has nothing to do with the Second Princess.
不关二郡主的事
I bullied you?
私怨
Su Ziying, when did I offend you?
苏子婴 我什么时候得罪过你啊
Su Ziying, stop there!
苏子婴 给我站住
How dare you try to be hired as a lieutenant
你竟敢冒充自己是女子
by pretending to be a girl?
想要考取副将
I'll beat you to death.
我打死你
Thousands of people in Huayuan City
花垣城内被你欺辱过的人
have been bullied and humiliated by you.
岂止千千万
How could you remember that?
你怎么可能会记得
Chen Qianqian. It's Chen...
陈芊芊 又是陈
When can you stop blaming me for what she did?
她的锅我什么时候才背得完
Now that he's confessed,
既然认了
let me get rid of this traitor for you, Qianqian.
那我便来替三妹除个内鬼
Guards!
来人
Su Ziying framed the Crown Princess.
苏子婴陷害少城主
Imprison him at once till a verdict is given.
即刻关押 等候发落
Got it!
是
Su...
苏
He's a traitor.
都不苏了
Chuchu.
二姐 二姐
Chuchu, listen to me.
二姐 你听我说
I really don't want to be the Crown Princess.
我真的不想当少城主
I'll find out another way to get it done.
这个事情我还会想办法的
At the foot of Weimeng Mountain,
威猛山下
when we played chess,
我与三妹对弈
you promised
三妹当初承诺
you'd return two things to me.
要将两样东西还给我
As for the position of Crown Princess,
少城主之位
you can take your time.
不急于一时
But as for the other,
只是另一样
Qianqian,
三妹
you need to step on it.
可要加把劲了
I'm sorry, Pei Heng.
对 对不起啊 裴恒
Qianqian, stop kicking yourself.
芊芊 你不必自责
I was so negligent
是我一时疏忽
that I let such a guy stay around you.
竟安排这样一个人在你身边
You almost got into big trouble.
还差点害了你
I don't care what Su Ziying did to me.
苏子婴的事情不重要
What worries me is that you got involved.
重要的是眼前这个事
I... I'll figure out a way to bring fair back to you.
我 我会想办法还你公道的
Well. Who on earth did it? I...
不是 这到底是谁干的 我
Nobody else.
还能有谁
It's me.
当然是我做的
You?
你做的
I've long found Su Ziying wanted to hurt you,
我早就察觉苏子婴有心害你
so I asked Bai Ji to keep a watch on him.
于是让白芨暗中盯着他
Just as expected,
果不其然
he tried to frame you for possession of the defense map,
他想用城防图栽赃你
so I asked Bai Ji to replace it with something else.
我就命白芨暗中替换了城防图
Don't worry.
你放心
I'll always protect you.
我会一直护着你的
Pei Heng can't do it,
裴恒做不到的事
but I can do.
我能做到
I'm sure Pei Heng will be ashamed
我看裴恒以后还有什么脸面
to come see you again.
站在你面前
Aren't you ashamed to see me?
你有什么脸面在我面前
Is this the way you're protecting me?
你就这么护着我的
I understand you don't like Pei Heng,
你看裴恒不顺眼就算了
but why did you humiliate him and me?
你还羞辱他 羞辱我
Why did you do that?
你还这样做
Qianqian, what are you doing?
芊芊 你干吗
Han Shuo,
韩烁
are you so eager to be cheated on?
你是不是嫌你头顶不够绿啊
Wait.
不是
Bai Ji, it...
白芨 这
Why are they portraits?
这怎么是小人呢
Qianqian, I know nothing about it.
芊芊 这图跟我没关系啊
Bai Ji did all...
全是白芨
You're quick-witted.
这推脱得可真快
You just admitted personally
刚刚还口口声声亲口承认了
that you wanted to embarrass Pei Heng.
想让裴恒难堪
You must have ordered someone to draw it.
我看这图就是你找人画的
It...
这
Han Shuo,
韩烁
stop putting Bai Ji in the wrong.
你还冤枉人白芨 我说
Bai Ji, where did you get it?
白芨 哪儿搞的你
I found it just in the box.
就在少城主这箱子里呀
It was all of a sudden.
当时事发突然
When I took away the defense map,
我收走城防图之后
I dug out these paintings from the bottom of the box without extra trouble
随手从箱底翻出了这些图卷
and put them on the top.
放了上去
Without having a look at them,
也没看是什么东西
I closed the box.
就把箱子合上了
I hid them?
我藏的
Uh... No.
这 不对
There must be some misunderstanding.
这 这其中肯定有什么误会
Bai Ji must have got it wrong.
兴许是白芨他搞错了呢
The evidence is irrefutable, Chen Qianqian.
铁证如山啊 陈芊芊
Stop trying to put Bai Ji in the wrong.
你现在还想栽赃白芨
You're married to me.
你都与我成婚了
Why do you still keep the portraits of
你还留着裴恒这
Pei Heng?
图
You're
你这种女人
a fickle woman.
朝三暮四的
If you lived in Xuanhu City,
要放我们玄虎城
you must have long been abandoned.
早被休弃千百遍了
How about
那要不然
you divorce me?
你休弃我吧
Now that you care about it so much,
既然这么在意
let's get a divorce.
我们和离吧
You want to divorce me for Pei Heng?
你竟然为了裴恒要与我和离
You said you wanted to divorce me.
不是你说你要休弃我的吗
Yeah. I'm supposed to divorce you,
是 我本该与你和离
but I won't, considering that it's your first offense,
但我念在你是初犯
no,
不对
considering that you just did it out of curiosity
我念在你是可能很久以前
a long time ago
年幼无知
when you were still young and ignorant.
心生好奇
You've never watched them again
收来以后就再也没有看过
now that they're put at the bottom of the box
不然也不会压箱底
and you've even forgotten you once did that.
放了许久连自己都忘了
Right?
是吧
Yes.
对
Um. I'll let this issue pass.
那个 我不追究此事
I have to thank you for making an excuse for me.
我还得谢谢你给我想了这套说辞
-You bet! -Even I didn't think of that.
我自己都没想到
Do you really want me to divorce you?
难道真与你和离呀
In this case,
我这样
I'm broad-minded and generous, right?
算大度了吧
Yes, you are.
确实大度
But it's not finished.
不过这事还没完呢
What will Pei Heng think of me?
这裴恒以后怎么看我
How dare you mention him again?
你还敢在我面前提裴恒
Chen Qianqian, I'm warning you.
陈芊芊 我警告你
If you dare to mention the word "divorce" again,
若你再敢在我面前提和离二字
I...
我
Young Master, calm down.
少君 您消消气
You...
你呀
It's none of my business.
跟我有啥关系
Bai Ji, get out.
白芨 你给我出去
I was even reported because of some paintings.
看图还被举报了
The portraits are lifelike.
画得还挺像
Did you hear it?
你听说了吗
I'm ashamed to say that.
我都说不出口
The Crown Princess hides portraits of Minister Pei.
这少城主私藏裴司学的图
There is nothing to be surprised at.
有什么好惊奇的
She was like that
少城主还是三公主的时候
before she became the Crown Princess.
不就好这一口吗
Isn't it said the Crown Princess has returned to the right path?
不是说后来少城主改好了吗
An evildoer who reforms herself is more precious than gold.
浪子回头金不换
Maybe she's gone back to the original path.
兴许啊 少城主又改回去了呢
Don't you think what you said is weird?
这词是这么用的吗
Alright. Let's go.
行行行 走走走
We thought Minister Pei was attracted to the Crown Princess
本来说是裴司学倾慕少城主
and Young Master Han took away his love.
然后被韩少君横刀夺爱
But it turns out the truth is
没想到真相竟然是
the Crown Princess is into Minister Pei
少城主喜欢裴司学
and she even hides portraits of him in her mansion
家里还专门藏着裴司学的画像
to overcome lovesickness,
以供相思之苦
no, to ease the pain of missing him.
以解相思之苦
Pei Heng, I'm sorry
裴恒 对不起
I got you involved.
这次连累你了
But trust me.
不过你放心
I've destroyed all those portraits.
那些画我已经全部销毁了
Don't say sorry.
你不用道歉
I don't blame you.
我不怪你
I even did that to you.
我都对你这样了
Do you still not blame me?
居然都还不怪我
I don't mind.
我不介意
You don't...
不介
You have to.
你 你得介意啊
You can even lose your temper.
你还可以生气
You're into me
你心悦于我
and I'm also into you.
我也心悦于你
There is nothing wrong
此事
about that.
并无不妥
Wait.
等
You're into...
你 心悦于
Well. I mean,
不是 我的意思是
is it because of the love poem or the portraits?
是因为情诗还是因为画
I did hide the portraits there,
那画是我藏的
but I didn't look at them.
但不是我看的
Do you believe me?
你信吗
I used to be dull.
以前是我迟钝
We were engaged to each other,
虽然 我们有婚约在身
but I often avoided you.
可我总躲着你
I didn't know what I want
直到韩烁出现以后
until Han Shuo appeared.
我才明白我的心意
Qianqian,
芊芊
I won't let anyone take you away from me.
我以后不会再把你让给任何人
You don't need to
你也
look at those portraits in secret.
不必再偷看那些画像了
How could you be into me?
你怎么会喜欢我呢
Qianqian,
芊芊
this morning, I told Her Majesty
今早我已经向城主请求
I wanted you to divorce Han Shuo
你与韩烁和离
and remarry me now that we got engaged when we were kids.
我会履行我们自幼的婚约
From now on,
从今以后
I'll take care of you myself.
我亲自照料你
Mother!
母亲 母亲 母亲
Mother,
母亲
Pei Heng told you he wanted me to divorce Han Shuo
裴恒来求您让我跟韩烁和离
and remarry him?
让我跟他成婚
That's right.
没错
What did you say?
那你怎么说
I want to ask you a question.
我倒是想先问你
Do you like Pei Heng?
你喜欢裴恒吗
No. I don't.
不喜欢 真的不喜欢
You don't?
不喜欢
Then why are these found in your mansion?
不喜欢家里能有这个
You need to see through the appearance to perceive the essence.
这你得透过现象看本质
Don't be blinded by false impressions.
不要被假象蒙蔽了双眼
In my opinion, Han Shuo doesn't like you.
我看 你跟韩烁才是假象吧
He's a cold fish and stubborn.
他性子冷 脾气硬
He's seduced you into making mistakes several times.
还三番五次地引你犯错
I don't think he's the right guy for you.
我早就看他不合心意了
Pei Heng is different.
不像是裴恒
I see him grow up.
我从小看到大的
We know his background.
知根知底的
When Chen...
那之前那陈
When I decided to marry Han Shuo,
之前我抢亲
why didn't you stop me?
您怎么不拦着我呢
I didn't expect that
我也没想到
Han Shuo could live that long.
韩烁能活这么久啊
I even need to mediate the conflict between my husband and my mother.
我这还得调解婆媳矛盾
What are you murmuring?
你嘀咕什么呢
Mother, how about like this?
母亲 你看这样好不好
Let's each take a step back.
咱们都各退一步
I'll divorce Han Shuo
我可以跟韩烁和离
but I don't marry Pei Heng, okay?
但是你能不能不要把裴恒许给我
Look. I can't break Pei Heng's heart
你看我 刚伤完韩烁的心
immediately after I break Han Shuo's, right?
总不能又去伤裴恒的心吧
As the most handsome man in Huayuan City,
裴恒是花垣城第一美男子
Pei Heng belongs to all women.
他是属于全城女人的
You know I'm unfaithful in love.
你知道我这么花心
If I'm hard upon him or treat him badly,
我要是苛待了他 待他不好
I'll anger the public.
会引起众怒的
But you've already brought discredit on him.
可是你已经毁了人家的清誉
It's fair and reasonable
跟他成婚
that you marry him.
那不是理所当然的吗
Mother.
母亲
Fine. Forget about it.
好好好 罢了
I won't push you to marry Pei Heng,
我不逼你跟裴恒立刻定下
but as for the divorce,
但是跟韩烁和离的事情啊
I'll issue an order at a proper time.
找个日子 就传令下去
Mother, I think
母亲 我觉得
it's better for me to discuss it with him
你还是容我回去跟他商量商量
before you issue an order.
你再传令
It's just a divorce.
只是休弃而已
Why bother discussing with him?
为什么还要跟他商量啊
I have to do that.
他 他必须得商量
Han Shuo is short-tempered.
那韩烁他就是个老虎脾气
He's liable to fly into a rage.
一点就着
I need to persuade him.
得顺毛哄哄的
You don't understand.
你不懂的
The Crown Princess is straightforward.
这少城主 性情率直
She's the same as you
跟城主当年啊
when you were young.
就像一个模子刻出来的
She's changeable.
这说一出是一出
I don't know if it's the right choice
也不知道这城主之位
to let her be the Crown Princess.
交给她是对是错
Take the medicine while it's hot.
把药趁热喝了
Speaking of that, I heard
这说起来 小人听闻
the Second Princess
昨天 是二郡主带人抄了
had the Crown Princess's mansion searched yesterday.
少城主的府邸
Chuchu searched Qianqian's mansion?
楚楚带人抄了芊芊的家
Have I ignored something
是不是我最近
these days?
忽略了什么
Hurry.
快点
Go to Xingzi Mansion
你去星梓府
and tell the Second Princess
告诉二郡主
that I want to see her.
我要见她
I have something important to say to her.
我有话要跟她说
You even dared to frame the Crown Princess.
敢诬陷少城主
You should count yourself lucky that you're not executed.
没立刻处死就不错了
You want to see the Second Princess?
还想见二郡主
In your dreams!
痴心妄想
I want to see the Second Princess.
我要见二郡主
Let me see the Second Princess!
你让我见二郡主
How should I tell Han Shuo I want a divorce
我要怎么跟韩烁提和离
so that he won't get mad at me?
他才 他才不会被气死啊
Han Shuo,
韩烁
let's get a divorce.
我们和离吧
I've rekindled feelings with Pei Heng.
我跟裴恒旧情复燃了
Han Shuo,
韩烁
my mother wants me to divorce you.
母亲要我们和离
She said if I didn't,
她说如果不和离
she wouldn't let me be the Crown Princess.
她就不把少城主之位传给我
You know, I'll die
你知道我不当少城主
if I can't be the Crown Princess.
我会死的呀
I did it wrong.
我错了
Han Shuo, Chuchu and you are a real couple.
韩烁 你跟楚楚才是官配
I shouldn't have existed here.
我是多余的
What's wrong?
你怎么了
My legs are weak.
腿 腿软
I've said I don't blame you for those erotic paintings.
都说了 春宫图的事不怪你
Don't mention that word.
别说那三个字
It's the cause of all kinds of wickedness.
万恶之源
I'll stay away from pornographic material.
我再也不涉黄了
Han Shuo, actually I have something to say to you.
韩烁 我其实有话对你说
My mother...
母亲
My mother said we needed to...
母亲让我们和
Needed what?
和 和什么
Needed...
和
... needed a peaceful and quiet life.
和和气气 平平安安
I haven't got fully prepared.
还是再做点心理准备吧
Your Highness.
少城主
Minister Pei has something sent here for you.
裴司学派人送来东西
What is it?
送什么东西
He asked me to cook red bean porridge to dispel dampness.
裴司学送来红豆给我熬粥祛湿的
Red beans are symbols of love.
红豆乃相思之意
Our young master sent them to you
我家公子送少城主红豆为信物
to express his yearning for you, but not to let you cook porridge.
是为了表达相思 不为煮粥
Great.
很好
Pei Heng is determined to set himself against me.
裴恒这是铁了心要与我作对呀
Young Master Han, you got it wrong.
韩少君误会了
The City Owner will issue an order soon
城主马上就会下令
that you and the Crown Princess need to get a divorce.
命您与少城主和离了
When you married her,
当初您与少城主大婚之时
the flower parade, sacrifice to Heaven and the wedding ceremony were all cancelled.
未游街 未祭天 未拜堂
Your marriage is not legal.
根本不算礼成
So, our young master didn't set himself against you.
何来我家公子与您作对之说
Besides,
反倒是
he got engaged to the Crown Princess when he was a kid.
我家公子与少城主自幼婚配
They're...
怎么说也是
Bai Ji,
白芨
what are you waiting for?
还愣着干吗
Throw him out.
把他给我轰出去
As for that box of red beans,
那盒红豆
scatter them at the gate of the Pei's Mansion.
也给我撒在裴府门前
Red beans.
红豆
My red beans.
大红豆
I need them to cook porridge.
我得煮粥用的
I know why your legs were weak.
这回我知道你刚才为什么腿软
Get a divorce?
和离
I like you.
我喜欢你
I can't do without you.
离不开你
You know that, right?
这你知道吧
Yes.
知道
I'm honest,
我虽然性情纯良
kind and gentle,
为人和善
but I'll also lose control of myself
但若被逼急了的话
if I'm cornered.
也是会控制不住我自己的
You know that too, right?
这你也知道吧
Good girl.
乖
Your Highness,
少城主啊
what's bothering you?
你可是有什么心事啊
I feel that
我感觉香蕉他
Banana is weird.
变态了
Why?
为什么呀
Your Highness,
少城主
a new character showed up?
这又来新人物了
It's Peach.
水蜜桃
He used to desire for nothing
原本是一颗无欲无求的桃
and stand aloof from the world.
遗世独立的桃
But one day, he told Orange
谁知道这水蜜桃突然有一天
he loved her.
给这橙子表白了
What to do?
你说可怎么办
Did Peach dare to compete with Banana?
这水蜜桃 敢跟香蕉抢人
Isn't he afraid he'll be killed?
他就不怕香蕉杀了他吗
How about letting Banana kill Peach?
不如 就让香蕉杀了水蜜桃
Then the story will continue
这样矛盾又集中在
among the three of them:
橙子 香蕉和苹果
Orange, Banana and Apple.
三个人身上了
No way.
不行
Peach is Orange's original aspiration.
这桃子是橙子的初心
What does it mean?
这初心是个啥
It means he's her favorite
初心就是全剧中
in the script.
最喜欢的一个人物
Then why didn't Orange
这橙子为什么
accept Peach?
不接受水蜜桃的表白
In this case, Apple and Banana
这样 苹果和香蕉
would naturally become a couple.
就顺理成章地在一起
The four of them would be two couples.
两两一对 相亲相爱呀
Orange doesn't love Peach
因为这橙子对这水蜜桃的感情
like a woman loves a man.
不是那种喜欢
Obviously, Orange has fallen in love with Banana.
明显是橙子喜欢上了香蕉
Stop talking nonsense. It's impossible.
你别瞎说啊 没这回事啊
Impossible.
没 没这回事
The fruit circle is messy.
这水果圈啊 真乱
Your Highness,
少城主啊
with all due respect,
恕小人多嘴
I'm afraid you don't understand
您连自己笔下人物的心理
those characters' feelings.
都摸不清
So, how could the audience understand?
你说这要观众怎么看得懂啊
I even don't know
你现在别说是人物了
what I'm thinking about,
我连我自己心里怎么想的
let alone those characters.
我都搞不清楚
No wonder I can't write a good love story.
怪不得我写不好爱情戏
Look at the situation.
你看现在这剧情
It's messy enough.
都乱成一锅蛋花汤了
It...
这这这
Such being the case,
变成现在这个结局
how shall I develop it?
怎么还续得下去啊
Your Highness,
那少城主
is there any other plot or scene you wrote?
您还有没有写什么其他的桥段
Maybe I can give you some advice.
让小人给你参详参详啊
Good question.
好问题
That day,
那天
the sister of Apple was going to
原本是苹果姐姐
throw an embroidered ball to choose a husband.
绣球定亲的日子
Your Highness.
郡主 郡主 郡主
Pass it to me.
传给我
The Princess Royal has chosen
大郡主夫婿选定
Mr. Su Mu as her husband.
苏沐 苏公子
And then?
那再然后呢
But unexpectedly,
但是没想到 这香蕉
Banana bombed the city.
引爆了全城
Protect the Princess Royal.
保护大郡主
Mother!
母亲
It's getting close.
日子也不远了
The Double Seventh Festival is around the corner.
七夕快到了
Your Highness,
可是少城主
so many changes have happened
这现在前面的剧情
to the previous part.
已经变化得太多了
Some plots even didn't happen.
有些情节甚至都没有发生过
Banana couldn't make the same choice.
那这香蕉不可能还走老路啊
But
可这香蕉
Banana has been a fierce beast from the beginning.
他本来就是只大老虎啊
He'd been considered a sick cat for a long time.
被当了病猫这么久
I hope he won't demonstrate his power.
千万不能发威啊
Xuanhu City would destroy Huayuan City.
玄虎灭花垣
It's not a joke.
可不是闹着玩的
Young Master, let me pay my respects to you.
参见少君
Young Master, we're here
少君 我等此行
under the order of your father.
是奉玄虎城城主之命前来
We aim to
此行的目的
lay explosives in the city in advance.
是为提前在城中埋藏炸药
When the City Owner of Huayuan shows up
等七夕节
on a festooned vehicle at the Double Seventh Festival,
花垣城城主花车游街之时
we'll ignite the explosives to get rid of her.
点燃炸药 将其除去
Huayuan City will be thrown into turmoil without a leader.
花垣城群龙无首 必将大乱
By then, we'll collaborate with forces from outside
到时里应外合
to conquer Huayuan City at one go.
一举攻占花垣城
It's not the right time yet.
此事时机未到
I need to think about it.
我再考虑考虑
Your heart disease has been cured.
您的心疾已然痊愈
There is nothing to be afraid of.
如今我们还有什么好怕的
Do you want
难道 还要像现在这样
to keep pretending
假意对花垣城俯首帖耳
to be docile and obedient?
顺服一辈子吗
As long as we conquer Huayuan City,
只要我们强占了花垣城
the black stone mine
那乌石矿
will belong to Xuanhu City.
就自然是我们玄虎城的了
Do everything as I said.
凡事听我安排
You know the consequences of acting rashly.
你们知道擅自行动的后果
Got it.
是
How many people from Xuanhu City have arrived?
玄虎来了多少人
I heard it was 50.
听说五十人
Only 50? Unbelievable.
才五十人 不会吧
There is a limit to the number of visitors.
来者的访客是有人数限制的
They couldn't be so obedient.
他们才不会乖乖听话呢
Why is Han Shuo not here?
少君怎么没来
The Second Princess gets drunk
二郡主喝得烂醉
and stops Han Shuo on his way.
半路把韩少君给拦截了
Your Highness, why is Her Majesty not here?
少城主 为何不见城主
She's caught an illness,
母亲身体抱恙
so she can't be present.
不能来赴宴
She asked me
特意叮嘱我
to take good care of you.
一定要照顾好诸位
I don't have many rules.
我没这么多规矩
Make yourself at home.
诸位随意一些
Let's get started.
开席吧
Zi Zhu.
梓竹
Second Princess,
二郡主
let's say goodbye here.
韩某只能送到此处
I must go.
先行告辞了
Stay.
不要走
Han Shuo,
韩少君
since the day you saved me
自从那日被困在陷阱
when I was caught in a trap,
你来救我
I...
我
I couldn't help thinking of you.
我就总是忍不住想起你
You're drunk.
你喝醉了
I know
我知道
I shouldn't say these words to you,
我不该对你说这些话
but I just can't control myself.
但是 我就是克制不住我自己
I don't want to cause you any trouble.
我不想给你带来困扰
I just want you to know
我只想让你知道
how I feel about you.
我对你的心意
Are you sober?
清醒些了吗
Now that you don't want to cause me any trouble,
既然不想给我造成困扰
don't say those words
那不该说的话
you don't think you should say.
就不要说
No matter how you feel about me,
你的心意就算是死
just keep it to yourself till you die,
也应该永远烂在肚子里
because I don't want to know
因为我根本不想知道
and I don't want Qianqian to know about it.
更不想让芊芊知道
But Qianqian doesn't like you at all.
可三妹她根本就不喜欢你
If she likes you,
如果她喜欢你
she should have broken off
她会至今都没有拒绝
her engagement to Pei Heng.
裴恒的婚约吗
I'll make it invalid.
我会让这个婚约作废的
Why?
为什么
Why does Chen Qianqian have everything?
为什么什么都是陈芊芊的
Your Highness,
少城主
now that you're our young master's wife,
您是我们少君的夫人
you and I
那说来 您和我
are actually family.
应是一家人喽
Family?
一家人
Mrs. Han,
少君夫人
according to seniority in the clan,
按辈分来说的话
you should call him uncle.
你应该叫这位韩大人一声舅父
Now that it's the first time you've met each other,
这小辈第一次见面
you should pour him a cup of wine.
应该给倒杯酒啊
How dare you?
放肆
As the Crown Princess,
少城主乃我花垣城少主人
how could she pour wine for an inferior officer from Xuanhu City?
怎可对玄虎城小官倒酒
Minister Liu, you're wrong.
刘司银此言差矣
No matter what a high status she enjoys,
无论这身份再高 再大
she should also respect her elders.
也应该敬重长辈
Do people in Huayuan City
难道 你花垣城
just have no regard for superiors and elders?
就是这般目无尊长的吗
Fine. It's okay if you don't want to pour wine.
算了 不倒酒也行
How about performing a dance?
跳一支舞
All of us
我们哪
want to see
也想看一看
how women of Huayuan City dance.
这花垣城女子的舞姿啊
Mr. Han,
韩大人
speaking of seniors and elders,
目无尊长
please remember seniors come before elders.
也是尊在前 长在后
As Xuanhu City's envoys,
玄虎城使者
you're here to pay a formal visit to the City Owner of Huayuan,
前来拜见花垣城主
so the Crown Princess is superior to you.
便是少城主为尊
Besides, in Huayuan City,
况且在我们花垣城
women are superior to men.
也是女子为尊
Young Master Han
你们少君
is the Crown Princess's husband for the time being,
虽然暂时还是少城主丈夫
but he may get a divorce anytime.
可少城主却随时可以将他休弃
Could it be that
还是说各位使者
you just aim to
本来就想带韩少君
take Young Master Han back to Xuanhu City?
一同回玄虎城
Who are you?
你是何人
Now that women are superior in Huayuan City,
既然花垣城女子为尊
how can you speak here?
哪有你一个男人说话的地方
I'm Pei Heng.
在下裴恒
The former Minister of Defense is my late father.
已故裴司军之子
I'm the Crown Princess's fiancé.
少城主的未婚夫婿
The banquet just started.
这宴会才刚刚开始
Don't lose your temper.
火气都别这么大嘛
Calm down.
都冷静点
They have a long journey
人家千里迢迢
from Xuanhu City to Huayuan City.
从玄虎城到花垣城
They just want us to pour wine and perform a dance.
不就是倒个酒 跳个舞吗
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
这有什么丢人的
Zi Rui, go.
梓锐 去
Ask Han Shuo to come here
把少君请来
and perform a dance for them.
给大家跳个舞助助兴
You've never had a chance
你们肯定是没有见过
to see him dance, right?
你们家少君跳舞吧
It's impossible to do that in Xuanhu City,
在玄虎城见不着
but you can do that in Huayuan City.
但是在花垣倒是可以一饱眼福
I remember
我记得我第一次
it's in the Music and Dance Academy
见少君跳舞是在
that I saw him dance for the first time.
教坊司
It's really special.
当时还别有一番风味呢
Hurry.
快去快去
Forget about it.
算了
I suddenly lost interest in it.
突然没了兴致
I don't want to watch.
不看了
Not interested?
没兴致了
What a pity.
那不巧了
Come back.
别去了
Drink wine.
喝酒吧
I knew you didn't dare to let him suffer wrong.
就知道你们不敢让他受委屈
Neither do I.
我也不敢啊
The medicine is getting bitter.
这药是越来越苦了
It seems running wild works sometimes.
看来胡闹也有管用的时候啊
You don't know how embarrassed
那些使者的脸色呀
those envoys are.
别提有多难看了
Those guys from Xuanhu City have gone too far.
玄虎城这群人真是放肆
They came here half a month ahead of time.
竟然提前来了半个月
They must have ulterior motives.
一定是有所图谋
Ask Chuchu
让楚楚率军
to investigate it in secret
就以加强城防为由
in the name of improving public safety.
暗中调查
Got it.
是
As for Han Shuo,
至于韩烁
his issue has something to do with the two cities.
事关两城纷争
I can't let him keep staying by Qianqian's side.
让他留在芊芊身边
He's a hidden trouble anyway.
始终是个变数
How about letting them divorce?
不如 先令二人和离
I'd like to see
我倒要看看
what Han Shuo will do.
韩烁会有什么举动
Your Majesty, do you mean
城主的意思
you want to test Han Shuo
是想考验韩少君
on how serious he is about the Crown Princess.
对少城主的真心
I hope he won't let me down.
但愿他不要让我失望
Why did you
宴会之上
make things difficult for Qianqian on the banquet?
为什么要为难芊芊
We just wanted to
我们只是为了
deal her a head-on blow at the first encounter.
给陈芊芊一个下马威
We didn't aim to watch her dance.
并不是真的想看她跳舞
If I say I want to kill you,
我说我现在想杀了你
guess
你猜
if I'm serious or just joking.
我说的是真的还是假的
Young Master, don't be angry. I know I did it wrong.
少君息怒 下官知错了
Since I came to Huayuan City,
我蛰伏花垣城
I've been having a rough time to succeed.
步履维艰 熬到今天
You almost made me fail on the eve of complete success.
险些受你们牵连功亏一篑
Young Master, under the circumstances,
那少君如今这样
don't you think it's you that almost made yourself fail?
就不算功亏一篑了吗
For a woman,
少君为了一个女人
you let down so many people of Xuanhu City.
辜负了多少玄虎城人的期望
How dare you?
放肆
We're here to support you,
属下特意前来助阵少君
but you're hesitant.
可少君您却迟疑了
We had planned
七夕游街 夜袭城主
to get rid of their City Owner at the Double Seventh Festival
最后里应外合
and then conquer Huayuan City
一举攻占花垣城
by collaborating with forces from outside,
这些都是我们当初做好的计划
but you hesitated because of a woman.
少君却为了一个女人心软了
Young Master,
少君
we know you're in love with Chen Qianqian.
我们知道您钟情于陈芊芊
Your father has agreed
城主已下令
that she can stay by your side
灭了花垣城之后
as your maidservant
让她做个婢女
after we conquer Huayuan City.
留在您身边
Young Master.
少君
Young Master, the City Owner has issued an order that
少君 城主有令
you and the Crown Princess need to get a divorce
让您和少城主择日和离
so that she can marry Minister Pei.
让少城主和裴司学成婚
Here we are.
到了
Go in.
那您进去吧
Hold on.
等一下
The Crown Princess and Minister Pei...
少城主和裴司学
Look.
您看看 您看看
Young Master, the City Owner just issued an order
少君 这城主刚下令
and they already began to date.
俩人就私会了
I heard they were playmates in childhood.
听说 这俩人青梅竹马
They must have had an affair.
我看啊 早就勾搭到一起了
That's right, Young Master.
就是啊 少君
If we don't take actions and conquer Huayuan City,
您要是再不行动灭了花垣城
I'm afraid the letter announcing divorce
我看这休书
will be sent to Xuanhu City directly.
都快送到玄虎城去了
If our troops come southward
如果我们大军一举南下
and conquer Huayuan City,
灭了花垣城
then Chen Qianqian
那陈芊芊这个女人
will absolutely belong to you.
就是您的囊中之物了
Exactly.
没错
If you do that,
这么做
I'm sure you can get Chen Qianqian.
可都是为了陈芊芊呀
That's right, Young Master.
是啊 少君
Pei Heng,
裴恒
thank you for everything you did for me.
谢谢你总是为我着想
I like you.
我喜欢你
Of course I want the best for you.
自然为你着想
I'm married.
我已经成婚了
But your marriage
可你们之间
is mingled with Huayuan and Xuanhu's disputes and interests.
掺着花垣城和玄虎城的过往纠葛
He's not serious about you.
他对你并非真心
I know
我知道
you're bewitched by him for the time being,
你一时受他迷惑
but I can wait.
但我会等
Pei Heng,
裴恒
I like you as a friend,
我对你真的只是朋友之情
not as a lover.
并非男女之爱
Can you tell my mother
你能不能去面见母亲告诉她
you don't like me
你不喜欢我
and ask her to take back her words?
让她收回成命
Your Highness.
少城主
Yuanyuan is asleep?
长姐睡下了
Yes.
是
She spent two more hours on rehabilitation.
大郡主今日多做了一个时辰复健
She's tired
乏了
and wants to have a rest.
便早些休息
She asked me to have a chat with you.
让小人出来和您聊聊天
It's okay.
没事
It happens I need to stay alone.
我也刚好 清静一下
In the whole Huayuan City,
这整个花垣城
I have nowhere to go
除了长姐这儿
except Yuanyuan's mansion.
别的地儿我也不敢去了
Oh. Su Mu,
对了 苏沐
please take care of Pei Heng.
你照顾一下裴恒
I said something hurtful to him.
我说了很伤人的话
Your Highness, don't worry.
少城主放心
Minister Pei
裴司学看起来
looks vulnerable,
是个柔弱的人
but actually, he's strong.
但实则很是坚强
He won't take things to heart.
不是那种会想不开的人
You're lucky in love.
你情场得意
Of course you have no idea about that.
你自然是不知道的
Me? Lucky in love?
我 情场得意
Right.
对啊
You and Yuanyuan
你和沅沅两人
care about each other and always stay by each other's side.
心心相映 日日相守
You're...
那自然
Qianqian, what are you talking about?
芊芊 你乱说什么
Come on.
不是吧
You're going to throw an embroidered ball
七夕花灯会
to choose a husband at the Double Seventh Festival.
绣球定亲的情节都快到了
Could it be that the two of you haven't...
你们俩不会还
Did I just reveal elements of the plot?
我是不是剧透了
Yuanyuan, I remember
长姐 我突然想起来
I have something else to do.
我还有个事情要做
I'm leaving.
我先走了
I'll come here for you later.
我过两天再来看你啊
Your Highness, take care.
少城主慢走